Finding Aid for the Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers File Listing
  - Lightwood
    - Production Materials (Box 40, File 8)
    - Production Materials (Box 40, File 9)
    - Production Materials for Re-issue (Box 40, File 10)
  - River Rogue
    - Research (Box 40, File 11)
    - Research (Box 40, File 12)
    - Research (Box 40, File 13)
    - Research (Box 40, File 14)
    - Outline/Summary (Box 40, File 15)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 40, File 16)
    - Character Sketches (Box 40, File 17)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 40, File 18)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 40, File 19)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 40, File 20)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 41, File 1)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 41, File 2)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 3)
    - Production Materials (Box 41, File 4)
    - Production Materials (Box 41, File 5)
  - This Is Adam
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 41, File 6)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 41, File 7)
    - Character Sketches (Box 41, File 8)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 9)
    - Notes for Dramatization (Box 41, File 10)
    - Production Materials (Box 41, File 11)
  - Devil’s Elbow
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 41, File 12)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 41, File 13)
    - Chapter Summary (Box 41, File 14)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 15)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 16)
    - Production Materials (Box 41, File 17)
  - The Image And The Cry
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 41, File 18)
    - Chapter Outline, Chapters 1-2 (Box 41, File 19)
    - Chapter Outline, Chapters 3-5 (Box 41, File 20)
    - Chapter Outline, Chapters 6-8 (Box 41, File 21)
    - Chapter Outline, Chapters 9-15 (Box 41, File 22)
    - Chapter Outline, Chapters18, 19, 31, and Epilogue (Box 41, File 23)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 24)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 25)
    - Notes (Box 41, File 26)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 1)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 2)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 3)
  - Quest For The Pelican
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 42, File 4)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 42, File 5)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 42, File 6)
    - Character Sketches (Box 42, File 7)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 42, File 8)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 42, File 9)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 10)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 11)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 12)
    - Phonograph Records (Box 42, File 13)
  - In Pursuit Of Happiness
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 42, File 14)
    - Character Sketches (Box 42, File 15)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 16)
    - Production Materials (Box 42, File 17)
    - Production Materials (Box 42, File 18)
  - The People, The People
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 42, File 19)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 20)
    - Notes (Box 42, File 21)
  - Kitty Mood’s Cup
    - Research (Box 42, File 22)
    - Research (Box 42, File 23)
    - Research (Box 42, File 24)
    - Research (Box 42, File 25)
    - Research (Box 42, File 26)
    - Research (Box 42, File 27)
    - Research (Box 42, File 28)
    - Research (Box 42, File 29)
    - Research (Box 42, File 30)
    - Research (Box 42, File 31)
    - Research (Box 43, File 1)
    - Research (Box 43, File 2)
    - Research (Box 43, File 3)
    - Research (Box 43, File 4)
    - Research (Box 43, File 5)
    - Research (Box 43, File 6)
    - Research (Box 43, File 7)
    - Research (Box 43, File 8)
    - Research (Box 43, File 9)
    - Research (Box 43, File 10)
    - Research (Box 43, File 11)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 12)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 13)
    - Notes (Box 43, File 14)
    - Notes (Box 43, File 15)
    - Notes (Box 43, File 16)
    - Production Materials (Box 43, File 17)
  - The Mortal God
    - Research (Box 43, File 18)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 19)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 20)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 21)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 43, File 22)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 43, File 23)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 43, File 24)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 44, File 1)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 2)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 3)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 4)
  - A Time To Come To
    - Notes (Box 44, File 5)
  - Strangers In This World
    - Research (Box 44, File 6)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 7)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 8)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 9)
    - Music (Box 44, File 10)
    - Production Materials (Box 44, File 11)
    - Production Materials (Box 44, File 12)
    - Photographs (Box 44, File 13)
    - Photographs (Box 44, File 14)
  - I Choose To Die
    - Research (Box 44, File 15)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 16)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 17)
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 18)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 19)
    - Production Materials (Box 44, File 20)
    - Photographs (Box 44, File 21)
  - Campaign
    - Outline/ Summary (In Collaboration with Robert Penn Warren) (Box 44, File 22)
  - The Chair
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 23)
  - The Plaything
    - Outline/ Summary (Box 44, File 24)
    - Notes (Box 44, File 25)
  - Untitled- Brainard Cheney
    - Outline/ Summary (for a Thirty-Minute Radio Play) (Box 44, File 26)
    - Outline/ Summary (theme, the source of Power is Divine) (Box 44, File 27)
    - Outline/ Summary (devolution) (Box 44, File 28)
    - Story Ideas (Box 44, File 29)
    - Unspecified Notes (Box 44, File 30)
  - The Poetry Reviews Of Allen Tate
    - Production Materials and Dust Jacket Text (Box 44, File 31)
  - Untitled- Frances Cheney
    - Notes (Box 44, File 32)
  - Teilhard de Chardin
    - Research (Box 45, File 1)
    - Research (Box 45, File 2)
    - Research (Box 45, File 3)
    - Research (Box 45, File 4)
    - Research (Box 45, File 5)
    - Research (Box 45, File 6)
    - Research (Box 45, File 7)
    - Clippings (Box 45, File 8)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 9)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 10)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 11)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 12)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 13)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 14)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 15)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 16)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 17)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 18)
    - Manuscript (Box 45, File 18a)
  - Adventure II Series
    - Notes (Box 45, File 19)
    - Notes (Box 45, File 20)
    - Clippings (Box 45, File 21)
    - Photographs (Box 45, File 22)
    - Photographs (Box 45, File 23)
  - Howard Johnson’s Meals For Millions
    - Notes (Box 45, File 24)
    - Production Materials (Box 45, File 25)
  - Reviews of Brainard Cheney’s Writings
  - Lightwood
    - 16 Jun 1939- 31 Oct 1939 (Box 46, File 1)
    - 1 Nov 1939-29 Nov 1939 (Box 46, File 2)
    - 1 Dec 1939- Undated (Box 46, File 3)
  - River Rogue
    - 30 Apr 1942- 9 Aug 1942 (Box 46, File 4)
    - 10 Aug 1942- 23 Aug 1942 (Box 46, File 5)
    - 9 Sep 1942- Undated (Box 46, File 6)
  - This Is Adam
    - 1 Aug 1958- 24 Sep 1958 (Box 46, File 7)
    - 25 Sep 1958- 29 Sep 1958 (Box 46, File 8)
    - 1 Oct 1958- 30 Nov 1958 (Box 46, File 9)
    - 6 Dec 1958- Undated (Box 46, File 10)
  - Devil’s Elbow
    - Publisher’s Reviews and Undated Clippings (Box 46, File 11)
  - Stranger’s In This World
    - 3 Feb 1952- 1952 (Box 46, File 12)
    - 7 Jan 1956- 1960 (Box 46, File 13)
  - I Choose To Die
    - 23 Oct 1960- 30 Oct 1960 (Box 46, File 14)
    - 3 Nov 1960- Undated (Box 46, File 15)
  - Reviews of Frances Cheney’s Writings
  - The Poetry Reviews of Allen Tate, 1924-1944
    - Spring/Summer 1983 (Box 46, File 16)
  - Personal and Biographical
  - Biographic Materials
    - Transcription of Interview - Brainard Cheney and Lee S. Greene, 11 Feb 1975 (Box 46, File 17)
    - Cassette Recording of Interview- Brainard Cheney and Dr. Charles Crawford, 18 Feb 1981, 27 Jun 1981, and 7 Nov 1981 (Box 46, File 18)
    - Autobiographic Sketches by Brainard Cheney (Box 46, File 19)
    - Autobiographic Sketch by Frances Cheney (Box 46, File 20)
    - Clippings of Brainard Cheney (Box 46, File 21)
    - Clippings of Frances Cheney (Box 47, File 1)
    - List of works written by Brainard Cheney, with dates and publishers (Box 47, File 2)
    - Bibliography of writings by Brainard Cheney (Box 47, File 3)
    - Clippings on Brainard Cheney’s Literary Awards (Box 47, File 4)
    - Ford Foundation Grant New Releases (Box 47, File 5)
  - Financial, Land Transactions
    - Correspondence, 19 Apr 1904- 20 Sep 1909 (Box 47, File 6)
    - Correspondence, 20 Jan 1910- 17 Dec 1910 (Box 47, File 7)
    - Correspondence, 26 Mar 1911- 15 Nov 1913 (Box 47, File 8)
    - Correspondence, 19 Feb 1914- 20 Nov 1919 (Box 47, File 9)
    - Correspondence, 7 Jan 1920- 10 Nov 1921 (Box 47, File 10)
    - Correspondence, 10 Jan 1922- 29 May 1929, Undated (Box 47, File 11)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, B.B. Cheney, Sr. Notes (Box 47, File 12)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, 1841 Georgia Land Tract Deed- John Chancey to Amos Degan (Box 47, File 13)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, 1855 Georgia Land Tract Deed- Sylvannus Hilch to Joseph McKee (Box 47, File 14)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, 1855 Georgia Land Tract Deed- Robert Collins to Joseph McKee (Box 47, File 15)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, 1895 Georgia Sale of Land Notices-B.B. Cheney and D. M. McKee (Box 47, File 16)
    - Deeds and Land Ownership, Rough Notes on the Sale of Land M.L. Cheney and B.B. Cheney to South Georgia Land Co. and David M. McKee (Box 47, File 17)
    - Land Maps (Ware, Clinch, Echols and Charlton Counties, Georgia) (Box 47, File 18)
    - Notes, Abstracts of Titles, Certificate of Share Ownership, and other (Box 47, File 19)
    - Business Related (Oconee Brick and Tile Company, etc.) (Box 47, File 20)
    - Mortgage and Loan Forms (Box 47, File 21)
  - Financial
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Bills (Box 47, File 22)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Receipts, 1896-1922 (Box 47, File 23)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Insurance Papers (Box 47, File 24)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s War Risk Insurance For Brainard Cheney (Box 47, File 25)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Checkbooks, Aug 1919- Nov 1921 (Box 47, File 26)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Banks Statements and Cancelled Checks, Jan 1919- Nov 1920 (Box 48, File 1)
    - Tax, Social Security, and Royalty Statements (Box 48, File 2)
  - Family History
    - Brainard Cheney’s Honorable Discharge-U.S. Army, 10 Dec 1918 (Box 48, File 3)
    - Mrs. Mattie L. Cheney’s Will, 8 Sep 1919 (Box 48, File 4)
    - Martha L. Cheney’s Brenau College-Conservation Grades, Jan 1920 and May/Jun 1920 (Box 48, File 5)
    - Brainard B. Cheney’s Vanderbilt Academic Transcript (Box 48, File 6)
    - Clippings, most likely saved by Mrs. Mattie L. Cheney (Box 48, File 7)
    - Mattie L. Cheney’s Miscellaneous (Box 48, File 8)
  - Memorabilia
    - Tissue Paper for Kimono, 9 Aug 1916 (Box 48, File 9)
    - Frances Cheney, 1922-1924 (Box 48, File 10)
    - Frances Cheney, May 1924-June 1926 (Box 48, File 11)
    - Frances Cheney, Vanderbilt, 1925-1928 (Box 48, File 12)
    - Frances Cheney, 1959-1960 (Box 48, File 13)
    - Frances Cheney, Undated (Box 48, File 14)
    - Photographs of a Sculpture by William Edmondson, owed by Frances Cheney Photographs by Roy M. Neel, Frances’ Nephew (Box 48, File 15)
    - Portraits Of Brainard Cheney, 2 Pencil Sketches and a Clay Bust (Box 48, File 16)
  - Photographs
    - Early (Box 48, File 17)
    - Middle (Box 48, File 18)
    - Late (Box 48, File 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48, File 20)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Lists, Notes, Telephone Numbers, Drawings, Citations (Box 48, File 21)
    - Loose Ideas (Box 48, File 22)
    - Loose Ideas (Box 48, File 23)
  - Events and Activities
    - “Miss Cherry Blossom, Maid of Tokyo”, Play, 23 May 1924 (Box 49, File 1)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 2)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 3)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 4)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 5)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 6)
    - Tennessee Education and Dramatic Commission, (1956) (Box 49, File 7)
    - Sam Davis Outdoor Theatre Project, (1957) (Box 49, File 8)
    - Sam Davis Outdoor Theatre Project, (1957) (Box 49, File 9)
    - Sam Davis Outdoor Theatre Project, (1957) (Box 49, File 10)
    - Sam Davis Outdoor Theatre Project, (1957) (Box 49, File 11)
    - 11th Georgia Writers Conference, 30-31 Oct 1959 (Box 49, File 12)
    - The Seminars at Martinsville, 23 May 1960 (Box 49, File 13)
    - 18th Annual Symposium- Catholic Renascence Society, 3-4 Apr 1961 (Box 49, File 14)
    - Dedication of the James Agee Library at St. Andrew’s School, 14 Oct 1972 (Box 49, File 15)
    - Dedication of the James Agee Library at St. Andrew’s School, Clippings, 15 Sep 1972-15 Oct 1972 (Box 49, File 16)
    - Allen Tate 75th Birthday Celebration, Sewanee, Tennessee, 15-16 Nov 1974 (Box 49, File 17)
    - Alumni College Day (on James Agee), 1 Aug 1979 (Box 49, File 18)
    - Project R.A.F.T., (1981-1982) (Box 49, File 19)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982) Programs and Posters (Box 49, File 20)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Newspapers (Box 50, File 1)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Newspaper Clippings (Box 50, File 2)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Publishers Press Releases for Re-issue of River Rogue (Box 50, File 3)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Speech, “An Exile’s Return to the Altahama” (Box 50, File 4)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Speeches given at each city during festival (Box 50, File 5)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), School report by Kris Brodersen (Box 50, File 6)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Miscellaneous (Box 50, File 7)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Photograph of Log Raft (Box 50, File 8)
    - Project R.A.F.T. (1981-1982), Photographs (Box 50, File 9)
    - 33rd Annual Univ. of Tennessee Library Lecture, Frances Cheney “Writers as Readers”, 19 May, 1981 (Box 50, File 10)
  - Subject Files
    - Alcoholism (Box 50, File 11)
    - Book Reviews (Box 50, File 12)
    - Clippings, 21 Mar 1936- 9 Oct 1949 (Box 50, File 13)
    - Clippings, 7 Feb, 1952- 1959 (Box 50, File 14)
    - Clippings, 19 Nov 1961- Undated (Box 50, File 15)
    - Copyright Information (Box 50, File 16)
    - Dinner and Receptions, Event Programs (Box 50, File 17)
    - Housing, Urban League of New York City (Box 50, File 18)
    - Literary Information (Box 50, File 19)
    - Maps (Box 50, File 20)
    - Music and Theatre, Event Programs (Box 50, File 21)
    - Music and Theatre, Event Programs (Box 50, File 22)
    - Music and Theatre, Event Programs (Box 50, File 23)
    - Music and Theatre, Clippings (Box 50, File 24)
    - Obituaries and Memorials (Box 50, File 25)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, 4 Jul 1954-1 Sep 1956 (Box 51, File 1)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, 9 Jan 1957- 23 Jul 1957 (Box 51, File 2)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, 1 Aug 1957- 1 Nov 1957 (Box 51, File 3)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, 5 Feb 1959- Mar 1959 (Box 51, File 4)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, Undated (Box 51, File 5)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration, Clippings, John Kasper and Clinton Tennessee Segregation, 10 Nov 1956- 12 Dec 1956 (Box 51, File 6)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration- Clippings, Clinton, Tennessee, 11 Nov 1955-5 Dec 1956 (Box 51, File 7)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration- Clippings, Clinton, Tennessee, 6 Dec 1956- 15 Jan 1959 and Undated (Box 51, File 8)
    - Race Relations, Segregation, Integration- Clippings, New York Integration, 24 Dec 1958- 11 Oct 1959 (Box 51, File 9)
    - St. Andrew’s School (Box 51, File 10)
    - Tennessee Politics, Ellington’s Campaign, Clippings, 7 Jun 1958- 26 Oct 1958 (Box 51, File 11)
    - Tennessee Politics, Keynote Address, DNC, Frank Clement 13 Aug 1956, Opening Campaign Address by Buford Ellington 14 Jun 1958, and Book Jacket, Tennessee Senators By Kenneth McKellar, Published, 1942 (Box 51, File 12)
  - Associates Files
    - Davidson, Donald, Newspaper Clippings (Box 51, File 13)
    - Gordon, Caroline, Newspaper Clippings (Box 51, File 14)
    - Haun, Mildred, Memorial Issue of Tennessee Folklore Society Bulletin (Box 51, File 15)
    - Lytle, Andrew, Announcement of Publication of Andrew Nelson Lytle: A Biography, 1920-1982 (Box 51, File 16)
    - Lytle, Andrew, Newspaper Clippings from Sewanee News (Box 51, File 17)
    - Mims, Puryear (Box 51, File 18)
    - O’Connor, Flannery, Newspaper Clippings (Box 51, File 19)
    - O’Connor, Flannery, Three Articles (Box 51, File 20)
    - Porter, Katherine Ann, Newspaper Clippings (Box 51, File 21)
    - Tate, Allen, Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1976 (Box 51, File 22)
    - Tate, Allen, Newspaper Clippings, 9 Feb 1979-3 Mar 1979 (Box 51, File 23)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, Newspaper Clippings (Box 51, File 24)
  - Writings By Other Authors
  - Manuscripts
    - Gotto, Antonio--Evolution In Perspective (Box 52, File 1)
    - Gotto, Antonio--Teilhard de Chardin Manuscript (Box 52, File 2)
    - McCrady, Edward--What Can A Scientist Believe? Contents, and Chapters 1-2 (Box 52, File 3)
    - McCrady, Edward--What Can A Scientist Believe? Chapters 3-4 (Box 52, File 4)
    - McCrady, Edward--What Can A Scientist Believe? Chapters 5-7 (Box 52, File 5)
    - McCrady, Edward--What Can A Scientist Believe? Chapters 8-10 (Box 52, File 6)
    - O’Connor, Flannery-- A View Of The Woods (Box 52, File 7)
    - O’Connor, Flannery-- The Displaced Person (Box 52, File 8)
    - O’Connor, Flannery-- The King Of The Birds (Box 52, File 9)
    - O’Connor, Flannery-- Unidentified (Box 52, File 10)
    - Rubin, Louis-- An Image Of The South (Box 52, File 11)
    - Stahlman, James--Flight Over Richland Creek (Box 52, File 12)
    - Warren, Robert Penn-- Introduction to Re-Issue of River Rogue (Box 52, File 13)
    - Weyland, Norman-- Kit Carson In Chicago (Box 52, File 14)
  - Verse
    - Howell, Isabella--Inland (Box 52, File 15)
    - Pearre, Howell--The Second Act (Box 52, File 16)
    - Tate, Allen--All Is Brillig (or ought to be) (Box 52, File 17)
    - Unidentified (Box 52, File 18)
  - Reviews
    - Kirk, Russell--Textbook Evaluation Report (Box 52, File 19)
    - Tate, Allen (Box 52, File 20)
  - Articles and Essays
    - Abadi-Nagy, Zoltan--A Talk With Walker Percy (Box 52, File 21)
    - Bassett, Beth Dawkins--Converging Lives (Box 52, File 22)
    - Brown, Ashley--Flannery O’Connor: A Literary Memoir (Box 52, File 23)
    - Chapin, Katherine Garrison--The Courage of Irony: The Poetry Of Allen Tate (Box 52, File 24)
    - Coffin, Tristram--Six Unusual Texts From Mildred Haun’s Cocke County Ballads and Songs (Box 52, File 25)
    - Fain, John Tyree--Allen Tate: A Sheaf Of Letters (Box 52, File 26)
    - Farrell, David--Poetry As A Way Of Life: An Interview With Robert Penn Warren (Box 52, File 27)
    - Fitzgerald, Sallie--A Master Class: From The Correspondence of Caroline Gordon and Flannery O’Connor (Box 52, File 28)
    - Foley, Andrew--Once More, O Ye Laurels (Box 52, File 29)
    - Hagin, Chris--Frank Clement: A Decade Of Progress (Box 52, File 30)
    - Haun, Mildred--The Turkey’s Father (Box 52, File 31)
    - Kirk, Russell--The Art Of Choosing a College; The Enfeebled American Family; Is America Decadent? (Box 52, File 32)
    - Lukacs, John--Pornography and the Death Wish (Box 52, File 33)
    - Percy, Walker--Culture: The Antimony of the Scientific Method (Box 52, File 34)
    - Percy, Walker--Symbol As Hermeneutic In Existentialism: A Possible Bridge From Empiricism (Box 52, File 35)
    - Percy, Walker--Symbol, Consciousness, and Intersubjectivity (Box 52, File 36)
    - Presley, Delma--Life and Lore of Timber Raftsmen In Southern Georgia (Box 52, File 37)
    - Tate, Allen-- A Lost Traveller’s Dream and Appomattox, April 9, 1865: A Peroration a hundred years after (Box 52, File 38)
  - Speeches
    - Clement, Frank--Address Delivered at Gallatin, Tennessee, 31 May 1952 (Box 52, File 39)
    - Clement, Frank--Address Delivered at Lewiston, Idaho, 19 Mar 1954 (Box 52, File 40)
    - Clement, Frank--Address Delivered at Yakima, Washington, 20 Mar 1954 (Box 52, File 41)
    - Clement, Frank--A Record Of Betrayal, to the Tenn. Municipal League, Gatlinburg, Tennessee, 15 May 1956 (Box 52, File 42)
    - Clement, Frank--The Political Realism Of Regional Action, to the ALA, Miami, Florida, 22 Jun 1956 (Box 52, File 43)
    - Lukacs, John--The Trans-National Novel: A Possibility (Box 52, File 44)
    - Tate, Allen--Mere Literature And The Lost Traveller, Peabody Library School, 17 Jun 1969 (Box 52, File 45)
  - Reel to Reel Recordings
    - I Choose to Die, Act I, November 3, 1960 (Box 53, Reel 1)
    - I Choose to Die Act III (Box 53, Reel 2)
    - I Choose to Die Act I, Friday Evening, November 4, 1960 (Box 53, Reel 3)
    - I Choose to Die Act II, Friday Evening, November 4, 1960 (Box 53, Reel 4)
    - I Choose to Die Act III, Friday Evening, November 4, 1960 (Box 53, Reel 5)
    - Tape on Consciousness and Real Time (Box 53, Reel 6)
    - Pelican Story-Purgatory, Begins Song of Smyrna by Joy’s Friend (Box 53, Reel 7)
  - Frances Neel Cheney Library Career Papers
  - Correspondence
    - Outgoing, April 15, 1948-February 25, 1965 (Box 54, File 1)
    - Outgoing, June 14, 1970-August 1, 1975 (Box 54, File 2)
    - Incoming—Albertson, Dean- Duchac, Kenneth F. (Box 54, File 3)
    - Incoming—Fitzgerald, William- Lyda, Mary Louise (Box 54, File 4)
    - Incoming—Ma, Laurence J.C., Ryan, Dorothy E. (Box 54, File 5)
    - Incoming—Schlueter, Ray- Unidentified (Box 54, File 6)
    - Ashley, Lowell (Box 54, File 7)
    - Belay, Kesete (Box 54, File 8)
    - Blakely, Florence (Box 54, File 9)
    - Bobinski, George (Box 54, File 10)
    - Borchardt, Dietrich H. (Box 54, File 11)
    - Buros, Oscar (Box 54, File 12)
    - Doi, Masako (Box 54, File 13)
    - Eason, Helga (Box 54, File 14)
    - Fall, John (Box 54, File 15)
    - Friebele, Mary Lou (Box 54, File 16)
    - Fujikawa, Masanobu (Box 54, File 17)
    - Gitler, Robert, 1947-1968 (Box 54, File 18)
    - Gitler, Robert, 1970-1979 (Box 54, File 19)
    - Gitler, Robert, 1980-1983 (Box 55, File 1)
    - Gitler, Robert, Undated (Box 55, File 2)
    - Gray, Richard (Box 55, File 3)
    - Harrison, K. C. (Box 55, File 4)
    - Haynes, Frances (Box 55, File 5)
    - Haynie, Virginia (Box 55, File 6)
    - Hoyle, Nancy (Box 55, File 7)
    - Inoue, Kojiro (Box 55, File 8)
    - Ito, Akimasa (Box 55, File 9)
    - Katz, Bill (Box 55, File 10)
    - Kawaguchi, Aiko (Box 55, File 11)
    - Land, Ray (Box 55, File 12)
    - Lanier, E. A. (Box 55, File 13)
    - McGrath, Eileen (Box 55, File 14)
    - Moon, Eric (Box 55, File 15)
    - Park, Hyung-gi (Box 55, File 16)
    - Preece, Warren (Box 55, File 17)
    - Reece, Ernest (Box 55, File 18)
    - Szladits, Lola (Box 55, File 19)
    - Smith, Peter (Box 55, File 20)
    - Stone, Robert (Box 55, File 21)
    - Thuy, Dao (Box 56, File 1)
    - Tsuda, Yoshinari (Box 56, File 2)
    - Vermilye, Kristen (Box 56, File 3)
    - Vormelker, Rose (Box 56, File 4)
    - Waller, Theodore (Box 56, File 5)
    - Watanabe, Shigeo (Box 56, File 6)
    - Watts, Franklin (Box 56, File 7)
    - West, Robert (Box 56, File 8)
    - White, Carl (Box 56, File 9)
    - Wight, Edward A. (Box 56, File 10)
    - Williams, Wiley (Box 56, File 11)
    - Wright, Patricia (Box 56, File 12)
    - Wyatt, Robert (Box 56, File 13)
    - Wynar, Bohdan (Box 56, File 14)
    - Japan Related- A-D (Box 56, File 15)
    - Japan Related- F-J (Box 56, File 16)
    - Japan Related- K-L (Box 56, File 17)
    - Japan Related- M-N (Box 56, File 18)
    - Japan Related- O- S (Box 56, File 19)
    - Japan Related- T-Y (Box 56, File 20)
    - Japan Related- Unidentified (Box 56, File 21)
    - Unidentified (Box 56, File 22)
  - Writings, Research and Outlines, Articles